<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="seed_type">
        <item>None</item>
        <item>Land Race</item>
        <item>High Yield</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="fertilizer_level">
        <item>None</item>
        <item>Low</item>
        <item>High</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="irrigation_level">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="seed">Seed</string>
    <string name="fertilizer">fertilizer</string>
    <string name="irrigation">irrigation</string>
    <string name="hello">Hello World, GeoGameActivity!</string>
    <string name="app_name">GeoGame</string>
    <string name="about_descrip">\u0020 GeoGame is a virtual workbench for teaching and learning
	     through real-world geography. Created by the Geography Department with help from
	     the computer science department.</string>
    <string name="land_descrip">		\u0020	You may buy and sell land. Initial land costs
		from the bank are $300 per acre. Land
		purchased between families is negotiable.
		Obtain a Land Card for each acre your
		household owns.</string>
    <string name="wheat_descrip">		\u0020	There are two types of wheat varieties to
		choose from, land races (LR) and the new
		high yield cultivars (HYC) of the Green
		Revolution. HYCs have a high yield potential,
		whereas LRs have strong yield stability.
		\n
		\u0020If you use LRs, you hold back some of your
		previously harvested seed and do not need to
		purchase seed each year.
		\n
		\u0020If you choose to plant HYCs, then you must
		purchase the seed for $20 per bushel.
		\n
		\u0020The recommended seeding rate of HYCs is 2
		bushels per acre. You need to purchase new
		HYC seed every third year. As a result, the
		Banker will give 2 HYC Cards per acre (one
		for each year) to be placed on your Land Card.
		Return one of the HYC Cards to the banker
		when collecting money at the end of the
		growing season. </string>
    <string name="fert_descrip">		\u0020	You must decide if you will apply fertilizer.
		You can apply fertilizer at three levels, coded
		by the index F ranging from 1 to 3. When F = 1
		you apply 80 lb. fertilizer per acre. For F = 2
		you apply 40 lb. to the acre. For F = 3 you
		apply no fertilizer. The cost of fertilizer is $1
		per pound. Obtain a Fertilizer Card
		corresponding to the level of fertilizer you
		purchased and place it on top of your Land
		Card.</string>
    <string name="irrigation_descrip">		\u0020	You must decide whether you will irrigate. To
		be able to irrigate, you must install a tubewell.
		Each tubewell will cost $1,000 to install and
		will pump enough water to irrigate 25 acres.
		Each irrigation will cost $3 per acre. A typical
		full schedule for wheat would require three
		irrigations per growing season. A farmer
		will base the decision to irrigate on weather
		factors. You will be provided a weather
		index (W) to indicate how favorable weather
		has been for wheat production. An index of
		5 means very poor and dry conditions,
		whereas the top index of 1 means excellent
		conditions.
		\n
		\u0020 If you have the capability and have decided
		to irrigate, you will figure your frequency
		and cost for irrigation as follows:
		\n
		\u0020 Number of irrigations (Ni) = W – 1
		Cost of irrigation (Ci) = Ni × $3/acre
		\n
		\u0020 After irrigation, figure your yield for the
		given season using a weather index of W = 1. </string>
    <string name="yield_descrip">		\u0020 Yield will depend on the type of seeds you
		use, the weather conditions, and the level of
		fertilizer inputs you apply to the crop. The
		yield potential is 80 bushels/acre for HYCs
		and 45 bushels/acre for LRs. Since each
		type of seed responds differently to weather
		and inputs, a different equation will be used
		to calculate yield depending on the seed
		type you choose to plant. In place of the
		experience that a farmer would have about
		cultivars, study the graph below. These
		describe the relative performance of the two
		wheat types as affected by weather and
		fertilizer input level.</string>
    <string name="labour_descrip">		\u0020	You can buy labour or you can generate extra
		income by selling your labour. Wages are
		$240 per growing season (negotiable between
		families). </string>
    <string name="labourReq_descrip">		• 1 adult (male or female) per 2 acres of
		unirrigated land
		\n
		• 1 adult per 1 acre of irrigated land
		\n
		An ox can be bought or sold for $1,000. An ox
		will reduce time for field labour by 50%, but
		must be driven by an adult male. This will
		effectively double the output of 1 adult male
		from the owner(s) of the ox:
		\n
		• 1 adult per 4 acres of unirrigated land
		\n
		• 1 adult per 2 acre of irrigated land
		\n
		Children
		\n
		• At least 3 children are required to collect
		firewood, look after goats and fetch water.
		\n
		• If a family loses children and has less than 3,
		1 adult must stay at home.
		\n
		• No more than 4 children under 10 years of
		age are allowed in each family.</string>
    <string name="consumption_descrip">		• Each child requires 5 bushels of wheat/year.
		\n
		• Each adult needs 9 bushels of wheat/year.
		\n
		• If a family is in food deficit, people will die,
		starting with children.
		\n
		• If a child is born to a family, the new child
		needs 5 bushels. If the family has more than
		4 children, 1 existing child ‘grows up’ to
		become an adult and needs 4 bushels extra.</string>
    <string name="trans_descrip">		\u0020	In order for the results of the simulation to be
		realistic, your transactions must be "real." In
		other words, when you decide to sell land, you
		must find a buyer. When you decide to buy
		something, you must have the budget for it. If
		you want to work for wages, you must find a
		willing employer. </string>
    <string name="seqOfPlay_descrip">		1. Check that land and labour are on hand.
		Fill in household details on the
		Household Score sheet. Calculate
		consumption requirements.
		\n
		2. Weather card is drawn.
		\n
		3. Banker declares price of wheat, and Fate
		draws a Fate Card.
		\n
		4. Calculate yield based on the Yield
		Performance Graph. [Note: In year 1, all
		households start with LR seed.] Subtract
		consumption amounts per household.
		\n
		5. Sell your remaining wheat to the Banker.
		\n
		6. Conduct transactions with other
		households (labour or land) or with the
		Banker (HYC seeds, irrigation, fertilizer)
		for the following year’s crops.
		\n
		7. Determine your balance (Total Income
		minus Total Costs) and carry this amount
		forward on the Household Score Sheet as
		Savings for the following year.
		\n\n
		Repeat steps 1-7 a total of 7 times, or as long
		as time permits.
		\n\n
		At the end of the game, calculate your
		household’s final assets to show how much
		extra wealth the new technology has
		generated in the village.</string>

</resources>